<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on What they forgot to teach you about industry transitions from academia (WTF AITA)</title>
    <link>http://wtf-aita.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on What they forgot to teach you about industry transitions from academia (WTF AITA)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wtf-aita.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An intro to WTF AITA</title>
      <link>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-wtf-aita-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-wtf-aita-intro/</guid>
      <description>The talk The initial release of WTF AITA content took place at rstudioconf::(2022) in the form of a talk. Slides for this talk can be found here, and a video of the talk will be posted when available.
 Content and further development WTF AITA content consists of tools (often R-centric, but other languages/technologies are certainly welcome!) that help ease the transition from academia to industry careers. Current content domains include resume building, cover letter writing, and portfolio creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover letters</title>
      <link>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-cover-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-cover-letters/</guid>
      <description>Cover letters The WTF AITA talk highlighted the stevetemplates package for creating an elegant cover letter that renders from R Markdown.
Also mentioned was the notion of “cover accessories.” An excellent example of this is Javier Orraca’s org-themed Shiny demo Shiny app that he submitted as part of his successful Bloomreach job application. The GitHub readme for his project describes how this was done with bslib and thematic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolios</title>
      <link>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-portfolios/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-portfolios/</guid>
      <description>Portfolios The WTF AITA talk highlighted 3 ways to create a quick portfolio for yourself.
Make a GitHub profile Here’s a helpful walkthrough using the GitHub UI from Monica Powell. If, instead, you want to jumpstart this with 3 lines of R code, here you go!
# Make a project that is titled your GitHub user name usethis::create_project(&amp;quot;~/Documents/GHusername&amp;quot;) # Connect it to GitHub usethis::use_github() # Once in the project, run this to make your readme usethis::use_readme_rmd() Knit your changes to the basic template and you’re good to go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumes</title>
      <link>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-resumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wtf-aita.com/post/2022-07-27-resumes/</guid>
      <description>  Move from a 22-pager to a 1 or 2 pager! The WTF AITA talk highlighted Nick Strayer’s datadrivencv package for succinct, elegant resume building from R. See the talk’s resumes section in particular for how that looks.
That’s not the only option out there though! Here are some other great R packages that will help you shine!
 vitae resumer   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
